<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile Apps on Becoming a better Tester!</title>
    <link>https://www.vaishalidesarda.com/mobile-app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile Apps on Becoming a better Tester!</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 14:40:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.vaishalidesarda.com/mobile-app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Offline Testing of an Online App - What, why and how!?</title>
      <link>https://www.vaishalidesarda.com/mobile-app/offline_testing_of_online_app/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jul 2020 14:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.vaishalidesarda.com/mobile-app/offline_testing_of_online_app/</guid>
      <description>Offline testing of an online app!? If an app expects to be online, then, of course, it’ll not work offline! Whatever is there to test offline!?
Like I’d written recently, Testing is much more than merely validating Business Acceptance Criteria. A Tester helps see the app from the end user’s point of view and provides feedback to improve the quality and helps polish the user experience.
Having a great experience online and offline is one of the key points of engaging users in-app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going live with your app ... and then?</title>
      <link>https://www.vaishalidesarda.com/mobile-app/going_live_with_your_app_and_then/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 13:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.vaishalidesarda.com/mobile-app/going_live_with_your_app_and_then/</guid>
      <description>The mobile app market is drastically changing and everyone focuses on being noticed. After the app is launched, you have to be ready for continuous optimisation and improvement. Hence, highly frequent testing.
The QA role doesn’t stop once the app is live. Instead, the responsibilities continue in terms of regression and automation testing, signing off hotfixes and new releases - that too quicker, as customers don’t like to wait!
In the Pre-Launch phase, the business does the following :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile App Testing - Emulator/Simulators or Real Device</title>
      <link>https://www.vaishalidesarda.com/mobile-app/emulator_simulator_real_devices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.vaishalidesarda.com/mobile-app/emulator_simulator_real_devices/</guid>
      <description>Now that everyone has a smartphone and access to many free and paid apps, users and customers expect a certain level of professional and polished behaviour on their mobile devices. They know what to expect, what their devices are capable of, and expect to be delighted in terms of user experience, stability and interactions.
With new devices getting launched every month supporting different screen sizes, different resolutions, themes, Modified OS, combinations of OS and form factors, OS version updates, new features, it gets quite difficult to provide the Quality assurance and give the sign-off.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
